# Onubogu Chibuikem



nickchibuikem@gmail.com



+2348066060467



linkedin.com/in/onubogu-chibuikem-883711159



https://potfoilo.vercel.app/

### **Summary**

Hi I am Onubogu Chibuikem Onyedikachukwu. I am a talented software engineer with passion for building global solutions that will solve problems and improve society.

With my skills, experience and creativity, combined with my passion for software development and technology, I build cutting edge products that are beneficial to the end-users using the latest industry practice and pattern in my field.

You can rely on me to help you and your business achieve goals when software is needed.

### **Experience**



## **Senior Software Engineer**

#### Kafene

Apr 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

Kafene is a mission driven fin-tech company with the goal of empowering flexible ownership solutions.

Compile and analyse data, processes, and codes to troubleshoot problems and identify areas for improvement.

Collaborate with the front-end developers and other team members to establish objectives and design more functional, cohesive codes to enhance the user experience.

Liaising with developers, and other stakeholders to identify and implement new features.

Collaborating with Front-end developers to integrate user-facing elements with server-side logic.

Review and merge backend related PRs.

# Senior Software Engineer

#### Enyata

Apr 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

Currently working with a team in New York to maintain a Fintech product and building internal products.

Building reusable code and libraries for future use.

Build high-quality reusable code that can be used in the future

Liaising with developers, and other stakeholders to identify and implement new features.

Promoted twice within my first year for being customer focused and producing results

# aki

#### Senior Full stack web developer

#### AK Infotech Solutions Ltd. (AKI Solutions)

Feb 2021 - Mar 2021 (2 months)

Mentored junior developers on programming and best coding practice

Integrate third-party systems via APIs.

Collaborate on a daily basis with other team members to understand business requirements and user experience goals and pain points.

#### FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

#### CJGrandExchange

May 2020 - Dec 2020 (8 months)

Conceived and built optimised landing pages in ReactJs.

Integrated payment gateway and cross-browser compatibility which improved marketing by 50%.

Integrate third-party systems via APIs.

Continuously work to bolster front-end and back-end design and implementation processes in order to improve quality and efficiency.

Develop new user-facing features

Ensures the technical feasibility of product designs

#### Full Stack Developer

#### Freelance

Jul 2019 - May 2020 (11 months)

Build high-quality reusable code that can be used in the future

Develop functional and sustainable web and mobile applications with clean codes.

Troubleshoot and debug applications

Manage cutting-edge technologies to improve applications



#### Full Stack Developer

#### Errandboy

Apr 2019 - Aug 2019 (5 months)

Worked on a web application that utilized HTML, JavaScript, CSS3, React, Laravel and MySQL.

Write and review testable, scalable codes that support and enhance single page data visualisations.

Build modular, reusable components, codes, features and libraries for future use.

Support and nurture front end real-time feeds and APIs to ensure that data renders with little delay.

# **■ FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Dependable Orientals Ltd

Nov 2018 - Feb 2019 (4 months)

Designed and implemented a web application in PHP(Laravel) that was focused on connecting recruiters with job seekers.

This application cut setup time by 98% and significantly reduced human error.

Compile and analyze data, processes, and codes to troubleshoot problems and identify areas for improvement.

Liaising with stakeholders to identify and implement new features.

# Junior Freelance Web Developer

Freelance

Oct 2016 - Nov 2018 (2 years 2 months)

#### **Education**



Bachelor of Science - BSc, Computer Science 2015 - 2019 Programmer.

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

in JavaScript: Patterns - LinkedIn

#### **Skills**

Firebase • GitHub • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • JavaScript • Node.js • React.js • TypeScript • Laravel • Next.js • SQL